<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thechels.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thechels.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-14T02:48:25+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weak Notes</title><subtitle>// A working out loud, public second brain</subtitle><author><name>Mat</name></author><entry><title type="html">Countering Espionage and Foreign Interference</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Countering Espionage and Foreign Interference" /><published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Cyber compromises</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Threat actors use spear-phishing and social engineering, in the form of highly personalised messages aimed at tricking specific individuals into revealing sensitive information or clicking malicious links, to compromise accounts and devices. The proliferation of commercial spyware has enabled a wider range of actors to compromise devices</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber compromises]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Private Investigator - Common Mistakes That Helps Us Crack Cases</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/private-investigator-common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Private Investigator - Common Mistakes That Helps Us Crack Cases" /><published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/private-investigator---common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/private-investigator-common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Here’s one of my secrets for investigating…</strong> People often reuse usernames. By tracking a username across platforms, databases, and forums, you can build a surprisingly complete profile, even if the person thinks they’ve been discreet.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Curiosity, genuine, relentless curiosity, is the single most important skill in this profession…</strong> You have to be deeply interested in people, behaviours, patterns, and anomalies. It’s that instinct to ask why, to dig one layer deeper than everyone else, that often leads to the breakthrough. You can teach someone the technical elements, but curiosity, in my opinion, can’t be taught. It’s either part of your mindset, or it’s not.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s one of my secrets for investigating… People often reuse usernames. By tracking a username across platforms, databases, and forums, you can build a surprisingly complete profile, even if the person thinks they’ve been discreet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Diagnosis</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/diagnosis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diagnosis" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/diagnosis-</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/diagnosis"><![CDATA[<p>Last week my GP confirmed a diagnosis of ME CFS.</p>

<p>I’ve been off work since July and I’ve used my Mac for less than an hour in those several months. Basically to do a computer only task, and updating it.</p>

<p>Updates will be sporadic and will utilise some automations and workflows built on my phone (Drafts, Pythonista, Working Copy).</p>

<p>Apologies for any typos. Cognitive decline overwhelms</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week my GP confirmed a diagnosis of ME CFS.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacker Laws</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacker Laws" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it.</p>

  <p>(Brian Kernighan)</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it. (Brian Kernighan)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Free the web</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/free-the-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free the web" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/free-the-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/free-the-web"><![CDATA[<p>When website security doesn’t have fallbacks for visitors when using basic browser security tools.</p>

<p>The web used to be open, it’s now behind are verification, captchas and human verification as well as cookie banners.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It shouldn’t. But if the browser is overly hardened, such as blocking all cookies, it may cause the looping issue. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/cloudflare-blocking-me-randomly/620706">1</a></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Normally, instances like this are attributable to an ad blocker plugin. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/cloudflare-blocking-me/234356">2</a></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Disable ad blockers, update your OS and/or browser, try incognito mode, check your IP reputation, and/or try a mobile device. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/i-dont-know/535972">3</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Edit:</p>

<p>I had to sell my modest Premium Bonds to pay the bills and it didn’t work 4 times in a row on my mobile device.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’m sorry to hear that - please ensure you’re using a stable internet connection when accessing the website.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>VPN software, browser extensions and internet connection issues may interfere with the functionality of the website - please turn them off if you are using any.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In many cases issues can be fixed by making sure your browser is up to date or by using an alternative browser. Different browsers are more reliable on certain devices.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Premium Bonds are held with N&amp;SI backed by HM Treasury. The. Government.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When website security doesn’t have fallbacks for visitors when using basic browser security tools.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monthly Mixtape - Sep 2025</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Mixtape - Sep 2025" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025"><![CDATA[<p>What I’ve been listening to this month.</p>

<p><img src="/images/mixtapes/2025-09.png" alt="Monthly Mixtape 2025-09" /></p>

<ol>
  <li>The Middle - Jimmy Eat World</li>
  <li>Orange Crush (Remastered 2013) - R.E.M.</li>
  <li>Temptation Waits (2018 Remaster) - Garbage</li>
  <li>Round Here - Counting Crows</li>
  <li>A Murder of One - Counting Crows</li>
  <li>Linger - The Cranberries</li>
  <li>Road To Nowhere (2005 Remaster) - Talking Heads</li>
  <li>There’s No Future In Optimism - Garbage</li>
  <li>Meds (feat. Alison Mosshart) - Placebo</li>
  <li>English Summer Rain - Placebo</li>
  <li>The Wild Ones - Suede</li>
  <li>Everyday Is Like Sunday - Morrissey</li>
  <li>Zombie (2025 Remastered) - The Cranberries</li>
  <li>Leaders of the Free World - Elbow</li>
  <li>Irish Blood, English Heart - Morrissey</li>
  <li>Destiny Calling - James</li>
  <li>orange show speedway - Lizzy McAlpine</li>
  <li>Dead Flowers for Her - Skywatchers</li>
  <li>Here I Dreamt I Was an Architect - The Decemberists</li>
  <li>Avalanche - Nick Cave &amp; The Bad Seeds</li>
  <li>Little By Little - Oasis</li>
  <li>There Is a Light That Never Goes Out - The Smiths</li>
  <li>High and Dry - Radiohead</li>
  <li>My Insatiable One - Suede</li>
</ol>

<p>You can listen along on <a href="https://music.apple.com/profile/thechelsuk">Apple Music here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I’ve been listening to this month.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recommended RSS readers</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/recommended-rss-readers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recommended RSS readers" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/recommended-rss-readers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/recommended-rss-readers"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>RSS has been my preferred way to read content on the web for over a decade now (RIP Google Reader). It’s a clean, efficient and simple way to curate your own news and content from across the web.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ll leave it to Molly White to <a href="https://www.citationneeded.news/curate-with-rss/">much more eloquently expound upon the benefits of RSS generally</a>, but I wanted to add post a list of RSS readers that I recommend.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[RSS has been my preferred way to read content on the web for over a decade now (RIP Google Reader). It’s a clean, efficient and simple way to curate your own news and content from across the web.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why NetNewsWire Is Not a Web App</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/why-netnewswire-is-not-a-web-app" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why NetNewsWire Is Not a Web App" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/why-netnewswire-is-not-a-web-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/why-netnewswire-is-not-a-web-app"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>But what if I wanted to do a web app, in addition to or instead of a native app?</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I can picture a future, as I bet you can, where RSS readers aren’t allowed on any app store, and we’re essentially required to use billionaire-owned social media and platform-owned news apps.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>But there are issues with making NetNewsWire a web app.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[But what if I wanted to do a web app, in addition to or instead of a native app?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple on the Digital Markets Act</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/apple-on-the-digital-markets-act" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple on the Digital Markets Act" /><published>2025-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/apple-on-the-digital-markets-act</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/apple-on-the-digital-markets-act"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Live Translation with AirPods and iPhone Mirroring are both <em>amazing</em> features. And EU users are missing out on them. I think Apple structured this piece exactly right, by emphasizing first that the most direct effect of the DMA is that EU users are getting great features late – or never. And that list of features is only going to grow over time.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Live Translation with AirPods and iPhone Mirroring are both amazing features. And EU users are missing out on them. I think Apple structured this piece exactly right, by emphasizing first that the most direct effect of the DMA is that EU users are getting great features late – or never. And that list of features is only going to grow over time.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS)</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/me-cfs-nice-guidelines" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS)" /><published>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/me-cfs-nice-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/me-cfs-nice-guidelines"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Summary</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <ul>
    <li>Myalgic encephalomyelitis or encephalopathy (ME) or chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) is a complex chronic condition defined by a specific pattern of different symptoms that impact a person’s quality of life and functioning.
      <ul>
        <li>There is typically a clear relationship between normal everyday activity levels causing a disproportionate escalation in fatigue, which does not improve with rest and is slow to recover.</li>
        <li>The exact pathophysiology is not fully understood.</li>
        <li>Symptoms typically fluctuate and can change unpredictably in nature and severity over a day, week, or longer.</li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li>A flare-up describes a worsening of symptoms, more than would be accounted for by normal day-to-day variation, that affects the person’s ability to perform usual activities. It is typically transient and resolves after a few days.</li>
    <li>A relapse describes a sustained and marked exacerbation of symptoms lasting longer than a flare-up and needing a substantial and sustained adjustment to the person’s energy management.</li>
    <li><em>Triggers may include acute infection or illness, overexertion, injury or trauma, other medical conditions, sleep disturbance, or stress. There may be no identifiable trigger.</em></li>
    <li>Complications include reduced quality of life, social stigma, loss of trust in healthcare and social care professionals, and impact on mental health, education, and work.</li>
    <li>There is no diagnostic test for ME/CFS. A diagnosis should be suspected if the person has the following symptoms for at least 6 weeks that significantly impact functioning and are not explained by another condition:
      <ul>
        <li>Debilitating fatigue that is worsened by activity, is not caused by excessive cognitive, physical, emotional, or social exertion, and is not significantly relieved by rest.</li>
        <li>Post-exertional malaise after activity.</li>
        <li>Unrefreshing sleep or sleep disturbance (or both).</li>
        <li>Cognitive difficulties.</li>
        <li>There may be additional symptoms associated with autonomic dysfunction, pain, the gastrointestinal tract, and sensory hypersensitivities, for example.</li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li>Investigations should be arranged to exclude alternative or coexisting conditions, including blood tests and urinalysis.</li>
    <li>Adults with persistent symptoms after 3 months should be referred to an ME/CFS specialist team for confirmation of the diagnosis and development of a personalized care and support plan.</li>
    <li>Review of a person with confirmed ME/CFS should be arranged at least annually in primary care, including:
      <ul>
        <li>Assessing current or new symptoms and investigating appropriately.</li>
        <li>Reviewing psychological, emotional, and social wellbeing; self-management strategies; and impact on functioning.</li>
        <li>Advising about sources of information and support.</li>
        <li>Reviewing and revising the specialist energy management plan, physical functioning and mobility, and physical activity or exercise programme (if relevant).</li>
        <li>Considering referral to a physiotherapist or occupational therapist working in an ME/CFS specialist team if needed.</li>
        <li>Reviewing the person’s support needs, including medicines management; education, training, or employment needs; financial and social care support.</li>
        <li>Managing any associated conditions and comorbidities including mental health, nutrition and bone health advice.</li>
        <li>Offering referral for cognitive behavioural therapy if the person wishes for this.</li>
        <li>Ensuring early recognition, planning for, and self-management of flare-ups or relapse.</li>
        <li>Providing a named contact in primary care and/or the ME/CFS specialist team to co-ordinate care and provide supports.</li>
      </ul>
    </li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary]]></summary></entry></feed>