<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thechels.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thechels.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-25T21:26:37+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weak Notes</title><subtitle>// A working out loud, public second brain</subtitle><author><name>Mat</name></author><entry><title type="html">Anti inflammatory medication in the treatment</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/anti-inflammatory-medication-in-the-treatment" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anti inflammatory medication in the treatment" /><published>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/anti-inflammatory-medication-in-the-treatment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/anti-inflammatory-medication-in-the-treatment"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Research evidence indicates that following an infection there may be on-going over-activity of the immune system occurring in both ME/CFS and Long Covid.</p>

  <p>As this may then result in low level inflammation, various types of anti-inflammatory drugs have been assessed as a possible form of treatment.</p>

  <p>The results from clinical trials that have been carried out so far have failed to establish that anti inflammatory drugs are an effective form of treatment for either condition.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Research evidence indicates that following an infection there may be on-going over-activity of the immune system occurring in both ME/CFS and Long Covid. As this may then result in low level inflammation, various types of anti-inflammatory drugs have been assessed as a possible form of treatment. The results from clinical trials that have been carried out so far have failed to establish that anti inflammatory drugs are an effective form of treatment for either condition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Key Offers for October 2025</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/key-offers-for-october-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Key Offers for October 2025" /><published>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/key-offers-for-october-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/key-offers-for-october-2025"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li><a href="https://bit.ly/3oD1nnS">£50 - Switch to Octopus Energy for £50 credit.</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://i.smarty.co.uk/CSj6iK">£40 - gift card when you join Smarty</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://aklam.io/91zWhU?">£75 - when taking a 1000mb YouFibre broadband plan</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://electroverse.octopus.energy/sign-up/magic?referralCode=aglow-louse-16571">£5 free credit when you join the Electroverse</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://tech.referrals.octopus.energy/ulLGI6SC">£25 - Visa card when you install an Octopus EV charger</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://join.monzo.com/c/tr0bxrb7">Join Monzo bank get up to £50</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="sponsor">Sponsor</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://cybaa.io/?ref=thechels">Monitor all your domains for security issues and get real time alerts with Cybaa</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="indie-app">Indie App</h2>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/uk/app/engman/id6747295473">Get the Engineering Manager Coach App on iOS now</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hiyd/id6746853559">Get Hiyd - the Jekyll companion App on iOS now</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/tomoz/id6748755747">Plan for Tomorrow, today either Tomoz for iOS - your simple view of tomorrow’s calendar events</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[£50 - Switch to Octopus Energy for £50 credit. £40 - gift card when you join Smarty £75 - when taking a 1000mb YouFibre broadband plan £5 free credit when you join the Electroverse £25 - Visa card when you install an Octopus EV charger Join Monzo bank get up to £50]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“What to Do When Before You Die”</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/what-to-do-when-you-die" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“What to Do When Before You Die”" /><published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/what-to-do-when-you-die</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/what-to-do-when-you-die"><![CDATA[<h2 id="essential-estate-planning-checklist">Essential Estate Planning Checklist</h2>

<h3 id="legal-documents">Legal Documents</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Will. Ensure you have a current, legally valid will so your assets are distributed according to your wishes.</li>
  <li>Lasting Power of Attorney. This is critical in case you cannot function cognitively to manage your own affairs, allowing someone you trust to make decisions on your behalf.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="documentation">Documentation</h3>

<ul>
  <li>“When I Die” folder or notebook. Create centralized documentation of all essential information so your loved ones can find what they need (check out Meaningful Money website and podcast for more on this—they typically cover it once a year).</li>
  <li>Records of businesses, banks, bills, and assets. Maintain comprehensive records and set an annual reminder to review and update these so nothing is overlooked.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="communication-and-access">Communication and Access</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Quarterly sessions with spouse or next of kin. Schedule regular reviews of your financial situation together so they understand your affairs before an emergency arises.</li>
  <li>Joint names on bills. Where possible, add your spouse or next of kin to accounts so they can manage them without legal complications.</li>
  <li>Shared password vault. Use a password manager with shared access for accounts that can’t be joint, ensuring your family can access critical accounts when needed (good practice anyway).</li>
  <li>Shared email account. Consider setting one up for household management so important communications aren’t lost in a personal inbox.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="insurance">Insurance</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Comprehensive coverage. If you can afford it, protect your family against financial hardship by considering:
    <ul>
      <li>Critical illness cover to replace income if you’re diagnosed with a serious condition.</li>
      <li>Income protection to cover regular expenses if you can’t work.</li>
      <li>Death or life cover to provide financial security for dependents.</li>
      <li>Medical insurance to avoid depleting savings for healthcare costs.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="pensions">Pensions</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Expression of wishes. Ensure all pensions have up-to-date beneficiary designations, as pensions are at the administrator’s discretion and millions still list ex-spouses as beneficiaries, which often causes family disputes.</li>
  <li>Consolidation. Simplify by consolidating workplace pensions into one SIPP where appropriate, making them easier to track and manage (except defined benefit schemes—get professional advice if needed).</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="digital-legacy">Digital Legacy</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Online legacy services. Some platforms like Meta (neé Facebook) allow you to transfer ownership to another user upon proof of death, preserving memories and access.</li>
  <li>Social media and digital accounts. Decide what you want to happen to each account so your digital presence is handled according to your wishes.</li>
  <li>Digital downsizing. Take stock of all accounts and eliminate unnecessary ones, reducing the burden on those managing your estate.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="final-wishes">Final Wishes</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Document your preferences. Put in writing what you want when the inevitable happens so your family isn’t left guessing during an emotional time:
    <ul>
      <li>Burial or cremation preferences.</li>
      <li>Wake or memorial service details.</li>
      <li>Music playlist for the service.</li>
      <li>Poems and readings you’d like included.</li>
      <li>Any other specific requests or wishes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>This comprehensive checklist ensures your affairs are in order and reduces the administrative and emotional burden on loved ones during difficult times.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="finance" /><category term="planning" /><category term="estate" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Essential Estate Planning Checklist]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AWS CEO on AI replacing junior staff</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/aws-ceo-on-ai-replacing-junior-staff" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AWS CEO on AI replacing junior staff" /><published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/aws-ceo-on-ai-replacing-junior-staff</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/aws-ceo-on-ai-replacing-junior-staff"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Amazon Web Services CEO Matt Garman has suggested firing junior workers because AI can do their jobs is “the dumbest thing I’ve ever heard.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services CEO Matt Garman has suggested firing junior workers because AI can do their jobs is “the dumbest thing I’ve ever heard.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Countering Espionage and Foreign Interference</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Countering Espionage and Foreign Interference" /><published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/countering-espionage-and-foreign-interference"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Cyber compromises</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Threat actors use spear-phishing and social engineering, in the form of highly personalised messages aimed at tricking specific individuals into revealing sensitive information or clicking malicious links, to compromise accounts and devices. The proliferation of commercial spyware has enabled a wider range of actors to compromise devices</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber compromises]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Private Investigator - Common Mistakes That Helps Us Crack Cases</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/private-investigator-common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Private Investigator - Common Mistakes That Helps Us Crack Cases" /><published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/private-investigator---common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/private-investigator-common-mistakes-that-helps-us-crack-cases"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Here’s one of my secrets for investigating…</strong> People often reuse usernames. By tracking a username across platforms, databases, and forums, you can build a surprisingly complete profile, even if the person thinks they’ve been discreet.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Curiosity, genuine, relentless curiosity, is the single most important skill in this profession…</strong> You have to be deeply interested in people, behaviours, patterns, and anomalies. It’s that instinct to ask why, to dig one layer deeper than everyone else, that often leads to the breakthrough. You can teach someone the technical elements, but curiosity, in my opinion, can’t be taught. It’s either part of your mindset, or it’s not.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s one of my secrets for investigating… People often reuse usernames. By tracking a username across platforms, databases, and forums, you can build a surprisingly complete profile, even if the person thinks they’ve been discreet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Diagnosis</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/diagnosis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diagnosis" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/diagnosis-</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/diagnosis"><![CDATA[<p>Last week my GP confirmed a diagnosis of ME CFS.</p>

<p>I’ve been off work since July and I’ve used my Mac for less than an hour in those several months. Basically to do a computer only task, and updating it.</p>

<p>Updates will be sporadic and will utilise some automations and workflows built on my phone (Drafts, Pythonista, Working Copy).</p>

<p>Apologies for any typos. Cognitive decline overwhelms</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week my GP confirmed a diagnosis of ME CFS.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacker Laws</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacker Laws" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/hacker-laws"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it.</p>

  <p>(Brian Kernighan)</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it. (Brian Kernighan)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Free the web</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/free-the-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free the web" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/free-the-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/free-the-web"><![CDATA[<p>When website security doesn’t have fallbacks for visitors when using basic browser security tools.</p>

<p>The web used to be open, it’s now behind are verification, captchas and human verification as well as cookie banners.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It shouldn’t. But if the browser is overly hardened, such as blocking all cookies, it may cause the looping issue. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/cloudflare-blocking-me-randomly/620706">1</a></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Normally, instances like this are attributable to an ad blocker plugin. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/cloudflare-blocking-me/234356">2</a></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Disable ad blockers, update your OS and/or browser, try incognito mode, check your IP reputation, and/or try a mobile device. <a href="https://community.cloudflare.com/t/i-dont-know/535972">3</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Edit:</p>

<p>I had to sell my modest Premium Bonds to pay the bills and it didn’t work 4 times in a row on my mobile device.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’m sorry to hear that - please ensure you’re using a stable internet connection when accessing the website.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>VPN software, browser extensions and internet connection issues may interfere with the functionality of the website - please turn them off if you are using any.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In many cases issues can be fixed by making sure your browser is up to date or by using an alternative browser. Different browsers are more reliable on certain devices.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Premium Bonds are held with N&amp;SI backed by HM Treasury. The. Government.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When website security doesn’t have fallbacks for visitors when using basic browser security tools.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monthly Mixtape - Sep 2025</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Mixtape - Sep 2025" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-musix-09-2025"><![CDATA[<p>What I’ve been listening to this month.</p>

<p><img src="/images/mixtapes/2025-09.png" alt="Monthly Mixtape 2025-09" /></p>

<ol>
  <li>The Middle - Jimmy Eat World</li>
  <li>Orange Crush (Remastered 2013) - R.E.M.</li>
  <li>Temptation Waits (2018 Remaster) - Garbage</li>
  <li>Round Here - Counting Crows</li>
  <li>A Murder of One - Counting Crows</li>
  <li>Linger - The Cranberries</li>
  <li>Road To Nowhere (2005 Remaster) - Talking Heads</li>
  <li>There’s No Future In Optimism - Garbage</li>
  <li>Meds (feat. Alison Mosshart) - Placebo</li>
  <li>English Summer Rain - Placebo</li>
  <li>The Wild Ones - Suede</li>
  <li>Everyday Is Like Sunday - Morrissey</li>
  <li>Zombie (2025 Remastered) - The Cranberries</li>
  <li>Leaders of the Free World - Elbow</li>
  <li>Irish Blood, English Heart - Morrissey</li>
  <li>Destiny Calling - James</li>
  <li>orange show speedway - Lizzy McAlpine</li>
  <li>Dead Flowers for Her - Skywatchers</li>
  <li>Here I Dreamt I Was an Architect - The Decemberists</li>
  <li>Avalanche - Nick Cave &amp; The Bad Seeds</li>
  <li>Little By Little - Oasis</li>
  <li>There Is a Light That Never Goes Out - The Smiths</li>
  <li>High and Dry - Radiohead</li>
  <li>My Insatiable One - Suede</li>
</ol>

<p>You can listen along on <a href="https://music.apple.com/profile/thechelsuk">Apple Music here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I’ve been listening to this month.]]></summary></entry></feed>