<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thechels.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thechels.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-25T18:37:35+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weak Notes</title><subtitle>// A working out loud, public second brain</subtitle><author><name>Mat</name></author><entry><title type="html">Is GitHub Ready For Enterprise-Grade SDL</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/is-github-ready-for-enterprise-grade-sdl" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is GitHub Ready For Enterprise-Grade SDL" /><published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/is-github-ready-for-enterprise-grade-sdl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/is-github-ready-for-enterprise-grade-sdl"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>GitHub is rapidly evolving into a platform that can support end-to-end enterprise software development, especially for teams prioritizing developer experience and automation. However, it is not yet a full replacement for Azure DevOps in environments that require structured project management, formal QA processes, and deep compliance capabilities.</p>

  <p>For most modern enterprises, a hybrid approach may offer the best of both worlds. GitHub can serve as the primary development and CI/CD platform, while Azure DevOps complements it with Boards and Test Plans for planning and quality assurance.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub is rapidly evolving into a platform that can support end-to-end enterprise software development, especially for teams prioritizing developer experience and automation. However, it is not yet a full replacement for Azure DevOps in environments that require structured project management, formal QA processes, and deep compliance capabilities. For most modern enterprises, a hybrid approach may offer the best of both worlds. GitHub can serve as the primary development and CI/CD platform, while Azure DevOps complements it with Boards and Test Plans for planning and quality assurance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Octopus doubles down on Seccl</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/octopus-doubles-down-on-seccl" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Octopus doubles down on Seccl" /><published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/octopus-doubles-down-on-seccl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/octopus-doubles-down-on-seccl"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Seccl now looks after more than £3 billion on behalf of more than a quarter of a million customers and expects to triple assets under administration over the coming year.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seccl now looks after more than £3 billion on behalf of more than a quarter of a million customers and expects to triple assets under administration over the coming year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remarks on AI</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/remarks-on-ai-neal-stephenson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remarks on AI" /><published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/remarks-on-ai-neal-stephenson</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/remarks-on-ai-neal-stephenson"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>This is the main thing I worry about currently as far as AI is concerned. I follow conversations among professional educators who all report the same phenomenon, which is that their students use ChatGPT for everything, and in consequence learn nothing. We may end up with at least one generation of people who are like the Eloi in H.G. Wells’s The Time Machine, in that they are mental weaklings utterly dependent on technologies that they don’t understand and that they could never rebuild from scratch were they to break down.</p>

  <p>To me this seems like a downside of AI that is easy to understand, easy to measure, with immediate effects, that could be counteracted tomorrow through simple interventions such as requiring students to take examinations in supervised classrooms, writing answers out by hand on blank paper.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the main thing I worry about currently as far as AI is concerned. I follow conversations among professional educators who all report the same phenomenon, which is that their students use ChatGPT for everything, and in consequence learn nothing. We may end up with at least one generation of people who are like the Eloi in H.G. Wells’s The Time Machine, in that they are mental weaklings utterly dependent on technologies that they don’t understand and that they could never rebuild from scratch were they to break down. To me this seems like a downside of AI that is easy to understand, easy to measure, with immediate effects, that could be counteracted tomorrow through simple interventions such as requiring students to take examinations in supervised classrooms, writing answers out by hand on blank paper.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Developers as Suppliers</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/developers-as-suppliers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developers as Suppliers" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/developers-as-suppliers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/developers-as-suppliers"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>I’m quite certain that everyone at Apple, right up to Tim Cook, would swear up and down that Apple <em>does</em> value third-party developers and does <em>not</em> treat them like they do suppliers.</p>

  <p>But ask iOS and Mac developers, small or large, whether they agree with Evans’s succinct summary above. I don’t know any who wouldn’t agree that Evans’s pithy take is largely, if not entirely, true. You’ll have to ask them in private, though, because, like Apple’s suppliers, they’re afraid to speak in public about the App Store.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m quite certain that everyone at Apple, right up to Tim Cook, would swear up and down that Apple does value third-party developers and does not treat them like they do suppliers. But ask iOS and Mac developers, small or large, whether they agree with Evans’s succinct summary above. I don’t know any who wouldn’t agree that Evans’s pithy take is largely, if not entirely, true. You’ll have to ask them in private, though, because, like Apple’s suppliers, they’re afraid to speak in public about the App Store.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quoting Bryan Finster</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/quoting-bryan-finster" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quoting Bryan Finster" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/quoting-bryan-finster</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/quoting-bryan-finster"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>If you’ve spent any time measuring value streams, you know that coding isn’t usually the problem. Having a clean flow of good information about the problems we are trying to solve is usually the problem. Not having a safe and fast way to deliver changes and get feedback on the quality of our ideas is also very common. I’ve yet to see an improvement effort that required us to focus on the coding part of the flow before fixing the upstream and downstream issues.</p>

  <p>As the cost to produce code continues to drop and the speed of doing it accelerates, it will become more obvious that apparent poor “developer productivity” was a symptom, not the disease.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve spent any time measuring value streams, you know that coding isn’t usually the problem. Having a clean flow of good information about the problems we are trying to solve is usually the problem. Not having a safe and fast way to deliver changes and get feedback on the quality of our ideas is also very common. I’ve yet to see an improvement effort that required us to focus on the coding part of the flow before fixing the upstream and downstream issues. As the cost to produce code continues to drop and the speed of doing it accelerates, it will become more obvious that apparent poor “developer productivity” was a symptom, not the disease.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’ve learned about writing AI apps so far</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/what-i've-learned-about-writing-ai-apps-so-far" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’ve learned about writing AI apps so far" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/what-i&apos;ve-learned-about-writing-ai-apps-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/what-i&apos;ve-learned-about-writing-ai-apps-so-far"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Is what you’re doing taking a large amount of text and asking the LLM to convert it into a smaller amount of text? Then it’s probably going to be great at it. If you’re asking it to convert into a roughly equal amount of text it will be so-so. If you’re asking it to create more text than you gave it, forget about it.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is what you’re doing taking a large amount of text and asking the LLM to convert it into a smaller amount of text? Then it’s probably going to be great at it. If you’re asking it to convert into a roughly equal amount of text it will be so-so. If you’re asking it to create more text than you gave it, forget about it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why breaking down work is important</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/why-breaking-down-work-is-important" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why breaking down work is important" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/why-breaking-down-work-is-important</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/why-breaking-down-work-is-important"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The team’s the thing
“Be ruthless with systems, be kind with people” - Michael Brooks</p>

  <p>Delivering high-quality software is a team sport, and we need to support each other. We should be aspiring to set up our workplace such that psychological safety and non-violent communication are first-class concerns rather than nice-to-haves.</p>

  <p>Work together, challenge the systems that make doing that hard, build an environment where good software is a natural outcome rather than a goal.</p>

  <p>tl;dr</p>

  <ul>
    <li>Identify where the value is.</li>
    <li>Do those things first.</li>
    <li>Optimise your delivery for fast feedback.</li>
    <li>Challenge things that hinder you.</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The team’s the thing “Be ruthless with systems, be kind with people” - Michael Brooks Delivering high-quality software is a team sport, and we need to support each other. We should be aspiring to set up our workplace such that psychological safety and non-violent communication are first-class concerns rather than nice-to-haves. Work together, challenge the systems that make doing that hard, build an environment where good software is a natural outcome rather than a goal. tl;dr Identify where the value is. Do those things first. Optimise your delivery for fast feedback. Challenge things that hinder you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Will YouTube kill the podcast industry?</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/will-youtube-kill-the-podcast-industry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Will YouTube kill the podcast industry?" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/will-youtube-kill-the-podcast-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/will-youtube-kill-the-podcast-industry"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>tl;dr – The podcast industry has long relied on the open nature of RSS to sustain a wide variety of small businesses. But that could all disappear if YouTube becomes the de facto place to publish podcasts.</p>

  <p>Podcast Movement Evolutions, a conference focused on ‘the business of podcasting,’ hosted 2,000 podcast professionals in Chicago on March 31-April 3, 2025.</p>

  <p>The dominant conversation? YouTube. With <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MGDvlsFaoVs"><strong>41% of people</strong></a> now using YouTube as their primary podcast platform, many industry leaders celebrated it as the future. They’re welcoming YouTube with open arms. I left feeling a growing sense of dread.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[tl;dr – The podcast industry has long relied on the open nature of RSS to sustain a wide variety of small businesses. But that could all disappear if YouTube becomes the de facto place to publish podcasts. Podcast Movement Evolutions, a conference focused on ‘the business of podcasting,’ hosted 2,000 podcast professionals in Chicago on March 31-April 3, 2025. The dominant conversation? YouTube. With 41% of people now using YouTube as their primary podcast platform, many industry leaders celebrated it as the future. They’re welcoming YouTube with open arms. I left feeling a growing sense of dread.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monthly Mixtape - May 2025</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-music-05-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Mixtape - May 2025" /><published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/mixtape-music-05-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/mixtape-music-05-2025"><![CDATA[<p>What I’ve been listening to this month.</p>

<p><img src="/images/mixtapes/2025-05.png" alt="Monthly Mixtape 2025-05" /></p>

<ol>
  <li>Sweetness - Jimmy Eat World</li>
  <li>A Design for Life (Remastered Version) - Manic Street Preachers</li>
  <li>Movin’ On Up - Primal Scream</li>
  <li>Intergalactic - Beastie Boys</li>
  <li>Time for Peace - The Little Shadows</li>
  <li>Planet of the Apes - Pinehurst Kids</li>
  <li>Street Spirit (Fade Out) - Radiohead</li>
  <li>Slide Away - The Vines</li>
  <li>You Held the World In Your Arms - Idlewild</li>
  <li>Silent to the Dark - The Electric Soft Parade</li>
  <li>The Black Amnesias - Hope of the States</li>
  <li>Transmitter - Sea Power</li>
  <li>Landslide - Allie Sandt</li>
  <li>Almost, So Close, Maybe - Mercer Henderson</li>
  <li>Strive - Yaron Herman</li>
  <li>Bigmouth Strikes Again - The Smiths</li>
  <li>Keep Watching the Sky - Skywatchers</li>
  <li>Nancy Boy - Placebo</li>
  <li>Shut up and Kiss Me - Pony Up!</li>
  <li>Whippin’ Piccadilly - Gomez</li>
  <li>Strict Machine - Goldfrapp</li>
</ol>

<p>You can listen along on <a href="https://music.apple.com/profile/thechelsuk">Apple Music here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I’ve been listening to this month.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Attitude is a choice</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/attitude-is-a-choice" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attitude is a choice" /><published>2025-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/attitude-is-a-choice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/attitude-is-a-choice"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>One thing you can’t take away from me is how I choose to respond to what you do to me. The last of one’s freedoms is to choose one’s attitudes in any circumstances.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One thing you can’t take away from me is how I choose to respond to what you do to me. The last of one’s freedoms is to choose one’s attitudes in any circumstances.]]></summary></entry></feed>