<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thechels.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thechels.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-14T06:05:15+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weak Notes</title><subtitle>// A working out loud, public second brain</subtitle><author><name>Mat</name></author><entry><title type="html">Rebranding and design costs</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rebranding and design costs" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps"><![CDATA[<p>Making intuitive interfaces and design systems that work for everyone is hard and takes time, but often the expectation is to deliver quickly.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Oh, and about the cost
A bit of hubbub has been made about the cost of the brand refresh, lamenting that a chunk of change (about half a million) was given to an agency to ‘only’ change a colour and move Dot.</p>

  <p>This perspective only focuses on the logo, and completely ignores the other additions to the brand that are being introduced over time. It ignores that everything was tested, prototyped, refined, and tested again dozens of times with members of the public. It might not be obvious from a single side-by-side graphic, but a lot of time went into interrogating what we had and experimenting with what could be added.</p>

  <p>It was the full-time salaried efforts of dozens of design, development, and delivery specialists for more than a year. By that metric, it’s actually quite cheap.</p>

  <p>The place we landed was well-considered and intentional. Just because the destination of that journey was a logo that intentionally looks quite similar to the existing one doesn’t mean that the money was wasted, or that creating something radically different would have been better value for money.</p>

  <p>A holiday isn’t a waste of money just because you return home at the end of it.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="brand" /><category term="GDS" /><category term="government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making intuitive interfaces and design systems that work for everyone is hard and takes time, but often the expectation is to deliver quickly.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Context engineering</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/context-engineering" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Context engineering" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/context-engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/context-engineering"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The term <strong>context engineering</strong> has recently started to gain traction as a better alternative to prompt engineering. I like it. I think this one may have sticking power.</p>

  <p>Here’s an example tweet <a href="https://twitter.com/tobi/status/1935533422589399127">from Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke</a>:</p>

  <p>I really like the term “context engineering” over prompt engineering.</p>

  <p>It describes the core skill better: the art of providing all the context for the task to be plausibly solvable by the LLM.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The term context engineering has recently started to gain traction as a better alternative to prompt engineering. I like it. I think this one may have sticking power. Here’s an example tweet from Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke: I really like the term “context engineering” over prompt engineering. It describes the core skill better: the art of providing all the context for the task to be plausibly solvable by the LLM.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Continuous AI</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/continuous-ai" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Continuous AI" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/continuous-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/continuous-ai"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>We’ve chosen the term “Continuous AI” to align with the established concept of Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD). Just as CI/CD transformed software development by automating integration and deployment, Continuous AI covers the ways in which AI can be used to automate and enhance collaboration workflows.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Continuous AI” is not a term GitHub owns, nor a technology GitHub builds: it’s a term we use to focus our minds, and which we’re introducing to the industry. This means Continuous AI is an open-ended set of activities, workloads, examples, recipes, technologies and capabilities; a category, rather than any single tool.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve chosen the term “Continuous AI” to align with the established concept of Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD). Just as CI/CD transformed software development by automating integration and deployment, Continuous AI covers the ways in which AI can be used to automate and enhance collaboration workflows.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural Language Web</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/natural-language-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural Language Web" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/natural-language-web-</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/natural-language-web"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p><strong>NLWeb</strong> simplifies the process of building conversational interfaces for websites. It natively supports MCP (Model Context Protocol), allowing the same natural language APIs to serve both humans and AI agents.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Schema.org and related semi-structured formats like RSS – used by over 100 million websites – have become not just de facto syndication mechanisms, but also a semantic layer for the web. NLWeb leverages these to enable natural language interfaces more easily.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NLWeb simplifies the process of building conversational interfaces for websites. It natively supports MCP (Model Context Protocol), allowing the same natural language APIs to serve both humans and AI agents.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Patients duped in records-and-payment scam</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/patients-duped-in-records-and-payment-scam" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patients duped in records-and-payment scam" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/patients-duped-in-records-and-payment-scam-</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/patients-duped-in-records-and-payment-scam"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Criminals masquerading as insurers are tricking patients and healthcare providers into handing over medical records and bank account information via emails and text messages, according to the FBI.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In a Friday security alert, the federal cops warned the public to be on the lookout for emails and texts purporting to come from health insurers and claims investigators. Criminals are sending these messages to both patients and healthcare providers alike in this latest healthcare fraud scheme.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Criminals masquerading as insurers are tricking patients and healthcare providers into handing over medical records and bank account information via emails and text messages, according to the FBI.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post-Exertional Malaise - The Key Sign of ME/CFS</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/post-exertional-malaise-the-key-sign-of-mecfs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-Exertional Malaise - The Key Sign of ME/CFS" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/post-exertional-malaise-the-key-sign-of-mecfs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/post-exertional-malaise-the-key-sign-of-mecfs"><![CDATA[<p>Post-Exertional Malaise (PEM) is the hallmark symptom of ME/CFS. It’s now recognized in long COVID patients too.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-pem">What Is PEM?</h2>

<p>PEM is unique to ME/CFS - it doesn’t exist in any other illness.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“inability to recover normally following physical, cognitive, or emotional exertion [resulting in] a level of fatigue that is more profound, more devastating, and longer lasting”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="key-features">Key Features</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Profound stamina loss</li>
  <li>Reduced functional capacity</li>
  <li>Worsened ME/CFS symptoms</li>
  <li>Autonomic dysfunction</li>
  <li>Metabolic problems</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="symptoms-during-pem">Symptoms During PEM</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Flu-like symptoms</li>
  <li>Brain fog and cognitive issues</li>
  <li>Headaches and insomnia</li>
  <li>Light/sound sensitivity</li>
  <li>Orthostatic intolerance</li>
</ul>

<p>Many patients become bedridden and struggle with basic tasks like showering or eating.</p>

<h2 id="common-triggers">Common Triggers</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Physical: Exercise, showering, standing</li>
  <li>Cognitive: Reading, computer use, conversations</li>
  <li>Environmental: Bright lights, loud sounds</li>
  <li>Emotional: Stress responses</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="timing">Timing</h2>

<ul>
  <li>PEM often starts 24-48 hours after the trigger</li>
  <li>Patients may feel immediate effects from orthostatic issues</li>
  <li>Duration varies widely</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-energy-debt-concept">The “Energy Debt” Concept</h2>

<p>Think of energy like money:</p>
<ul>
  <li>You have $1/day to spend</li>
  <li>Overspending creates debt that must be repaid with interest</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="management">Management</h2>

<h3 id="what-doesnt-work">What Doesn’t Work</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Graded Exercise Therapy as this worsens long-term outcomes</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-helps">What Helps</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Stay within energy limits</li>
  <li>Take frequent breaks</li>
  <li>Pace activities carefully</li>
  <li>Modify tasks (lie down, use timers)</li>
  <li>Ask for help</li>
  <li>Use delivery services</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="critical-points">Critical Points</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Warning: Repeated PEM episodes can permanently worsen baseline function.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hope: Avoiding PEM allows gradual improvement over time.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="key-message">Key Message</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Manage ME/CFS by being smarter, not fighting harder. Use discipline and intelligence to minimize or avoid PEM.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="medical" /><category term="chronic-illness" /><category term="pem" /><category term="me-cfs" /><category term="long-covid" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Exertional Malaise (PEM) is the hallmark symptom of ME/CFS. It’s now recognized in long COVID patients too.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GDS say Copilot AI saved workers 26 minutes a day</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/gds-say-copilot-ai-saved-workers-26-minutes-a-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GDS say Copilot AI saved workers 26 minutes a day" /><published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/gds-say-copilot-ai-saved-workers-26-minutes-a-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/gds-say-copilot-ai-saved-workers-26-minutes-a-day"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The United Kingdom’s Government Digital Service (GDS) has found that giving civil service employees access to Microsoft 365 Copilot saved them an average 26 minutes per day on office tasks.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Microsoft 365 Copilot provides generative AI assistance with various Microsoft Office applications like Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, and Teams. It allows workers to accomplish some tasks through a natural language chat interface instead of mouse movements and menu clicks.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The United Kingdom’s Government Digital Service (GDS) has found that giving civil service employees access to Microsoft 365 Copilot saved them an average 26 minutes per day on office tasks.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New GitHub Copilot limits</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/new-github-copilot-limits" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New GitHub Copilot limits" /><published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/new-github-copilot-limits</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/new-github-copilot-limits"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Microsoft’s GitHub this week said paying GitHub Copilot customers will now face monthly limits on certain types of high-powered AI requests, and will have to pay more if they want to surpass those limits.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Predictably, <a href="https://github.blog/changelog/2025-06-18-update-to-github-copilot-consumptive-billing-experience/">the change</a> has elicited grumbling from the GitHub Copilot users in online forums.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft’s GitHub this week said paying GitHub Copilot customers will now face monthly limits on certain types of high-powered AI requests, and will have to pay more if they want to surpass those limits.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build for the Web</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/build-for-the-web-build-on-the-web-build-with-the-web-css-wizardry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build for the Web" /><published>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/build-for-the-web-build-on-the-web-build-with-the-web-css-wizardry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/build-for-the-web-build-on-the-web-build-with-the-web-css-wizardry"><![CDATA[<p>Iterate quickly on a slow-moving platform, that is it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you’re going to build for the web, build on the web and build with the web.</p>

  <p>If I was only able to give one bit of advice to any company: iterate quickly on a slow-moving platform.</p>

  <p>In the last year alone, I have seen two completely different clients in two completely different industries sink months and months into framework upgrades. Collectively, they’ve spent tens, if not hundreds, of thousands of dollars rewriting entire projects just to maintain feature parity with the previous iteration. This is not meaningful or productive work—it is time sunk into merely keeping themselves at square one.</p>

  <p>They’re iterating slowly on a fast-moving platform.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iterate quickly on a slow-moving platform, that is it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Context Rot from AI</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/a-quote-from-workaccount2-on-hacker-news" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Context Rot from AI" /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/a-quote-from-workaccount2-on-hacker-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/a-quote-from-workaccount2-on-hacker-news"><![CDATA[<p>Via Simon Willison, a quote from a comment on  Hacker News by Workaccount2. Sharing here as I’ve found that I have inadvertently been doing this myself when wanting to move on with an agent and not have it carry existing context into a new request.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They poison their own context. Maybe you can call it context rot, where as context grows and especially if it grows with lots of distractions and dead ends, the output quality falls off rapidly. Even with good context the rot will start to become apparent around 100k tokens (with Gemini 2.5).</p>

  <p>They really need to figure out a way to delete or “forget” prior context, so the user or even the model can go back and prune poisonous tokens.</p>

  <p>Right now I work around it by regularly making summaries of instances, and then spinning up a new instance with fresh context and feed in the summary of the previous instance.
— Workaccount2 on Hacker News, coining “context rot”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="AI" /><category term="Hacker News" /><category term="context rot" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Via Simon Willison, a quote from a comment on Hacker News by Workaccount2. Sharing here as I’ve found that I have inadvertently been doing this myself when wanting to move on with an agent and not have it carry existing context into a new request.]]></summary></entry></feed>