<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thechels.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thechels.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-30T06:05:43+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weak Notes</title><subtitle>// A working out loud, public second brain</subtitle><author><name>Mat</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dia Browser Takes</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/dia-browser-takes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dia Browser Takes" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/dia-browser-takes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/dia-browser-takes"><![CDATA[<p>I like the simplicity of The Browser Company’s second browser. I had been using Arc as my primary browser as I preferred the left hand side tabs - particularly on my 34’ screen - for around a year.</p>

<p>Dia is a step back in feature set and an easy take is its chrome with chat GPT on the side. This largely true, but I can see huge value if you live on tabs and so it has your context.</p>

<p>This would be perfect for researchers both academic and creatives looking for their next long read as well as students.</p>

<p>I’m not yet convinced it’s the breakthrough I need, however it’s my default browser for now as the simplicity is there. I almost always have a dozen pinned tabs open, half a dozen others - it’s easy to ask questions on what’s open.</p>

<p>I also like some the prompt actions called Skills e.g., /morning gives me a daily rundown of news and eeather although this could improve over time. It uses my open tabs first and then broader internet context. For example I ask for a weather update and it fails, yet one of my tabs is my own site with a weather forecast on it.</p>

<p>I have adding /osint &lt;name, location&gt; for a decent factsheet about people, /tasks for identify things/actions to take from my open tabs (often github issues, news articles of interest)</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="app" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like the simplicity of The Browser Company’s second browser. I had been using Arc as my primary browser as I preferred the left hand side tabs - particularly on my 34’ screen - for around a year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Phone battery issues</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/phone-battery-issues" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phone battery issues" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/phone-battery-issues</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/phone-battery-issues"><![CDATA[<p>When a phone gets hot, very hot, because it’s processing something in the background and it doesn’t finish. It has crashed and you realise the battery has gone from 98% to 8%. You force close every app and have to leave your phone for an hour to cool down. Since October 2022 my phone was processing something and was always running hot and it’s hard a profound impact on its usability over the last six months.</p>

<p>Today I have the same phone but it is 3 year’s older. It’s battery says 80% but it’s actually only 5% and it randomly switches off, some days it’s 50% and lasts the day, some days it never seems to go above 20% despite having it on charge and not using it.</p>

<p>I turn the screen brightness down, turn off Bluetooth, force close all my favourite apps and charge it for about 15 hours a day just to be able to message people once in a while.</p>

<p>It randomly turns off if I try to send an email or make a call. Using maps in a new location or using any apps that do not have a shortcut or accessibility concessions.</p>

<p>Moving the phone from one charger to another doesn’t help and often makes it worse, somehow losing half its charge for the next 3 days.</p>

<p>Showing your phone to someone else doesn’t help, for that moment, on face value, it seems to operate like any other phone and is indistinguishable in its performance. Only living with it day in day out does one realise they need to get a new phone.</p>

<p>I imagine most people can relate to this if they’ve had a phone in the last decade. Now, imagine this was your body and you had a diseases or illness where there is no rebooting or upgrading of that ‘phone’ and no real evidence that your phone is actually broken.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="Me" /><category term="cfs" /><category term="Hiyd" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a phone gets hot, very hot, because it’s processing something in the background and it doesn’t finish. It has crashed and you realise the battery has gone from 98% to 8%. You force close every app and have to leave your phone for an hour to cool down. Since October 2022 my phone was processing something and was always running hot and it’s hard a profound impact on its usability over the last six months.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boost in support for patients with chronic fatigue syndrome or ME</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/boost-in-support-for-patients-with-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-or-me" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boost in support for patients with chronic fatigue syndrome or ME" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/boost-in-support-for-patients-with-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-or-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/boost-in-support-for-patients-with-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-or-me"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The plan published today provides the foundations for significant improvements in all key areas that affect people living with ME/CFS in England, many of whom currently struggle to access appropriate care tailored to their complex condition.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>As a priority, the plan will introduce new training for NHS healthcare professionals, featuring up-to-date learning resources to increase understand and ensure signs aren’t missed. This will help combat the stigma faced by people living with ME/CFS, which stems from a lack of awareness about the condition.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The rollout of neighbourhood health services as set out in the government’s 10 Year Health Plan will also see ME/CFS patients able to access care closer to home, with specially-trained staff able to support those with complex needs.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Minister for Public Health and Prevention, Ashley Dalton, said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>ME/CFS is a debilitating illness that can severely limit patients’ ability to participate in everyday activities, maintain employment, or enjoy family and social life.</p>

  <p>Today’s plan will help tackle the stigma and lack of awareness of this condition through improved training for NHS staff.</p>

  <p>And through our neighbourhood health services, we will ensure patients suffering from the effects of ME/CFS can access quality care, closer to home, as pledged in our 10 Year Health Plan.</p>

  <p>Our Plan for Change is transforming how patients experience care and this plan represents a comprehensive approach to addressing the long-standing gaps in care and support for people with these conditions, with patient access to appropriate care at its heart.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sonya Chowdhury, Chief Executive, Action for ME said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This is an important step for the ME community, long overlooked and under-served. The Plan must not be a token gesture–it requires a sustained, strategic commitment to care, funding, and research. Without it, meaningful outcomes for people with ME will not be achieved.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The plan includes increased funding for research, awarded through the National Institute for Health and Care Research, into how existing medicines can be used to for ME/CFS. This initiative aims to give patients access to a wider range of potential treatments.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The plan published today provides the foundations for significant improvements in all key areas that affect people living with ME/CFS in England, many of whom currently struggle to access appropriate care tailored to their complex condition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GOV UK issues a press release that the Delivery Plan on ME/CFS has been published</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/gov-uk-issues-presser-on-me-cfs-has-been-published" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GOV UK issues a press release that the Delivery Plan on ME/CFS has been published" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/gov-uk-issues-presser-on-me-cfs-has-been-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/gov-uk-issues-presser-on-me-cfs-has-been-published"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The Delivery plan has been published, however, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has so far failed to provide a link to the actual Plan!</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Delivery plan has been published, however, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has so far failed to provide a link to the actual Plan!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People - Principles - Process - Product</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/people-principles-process-product" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People - Principles - Process - Product" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/people---principles---process----product</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/people-principles-process-product"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The order in which we should focus is people, principles, process, and then product. You have to get the people right first. Then you decide on the principles that you are going to follow, i.e. what is your team’s culture. Once those are established, you fix the processes. Then finally, once all of that groundwork is laid, you can get down to fixing the product. Today, I want to walk through why I think this order is the correct way to approach situations, especially when we start new roles, start new initiatives, or need to pivot to something new.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The order in which we should focus is people, principles, process, and then product. You have to get the people right first. Then you decide on the principles that you are going to follow, i.e. what is your team’s culture. Once those are established, you fix the processes. Then finally, once all of that groundwork is laid, you can get down to fixing the product. Today, I want to walk through why I think this order is the correct way to approach situations, especially when we start new roles, start new initiatives, or need to pivot to something new.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tomoz App Launched</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/tomoz-app-launched" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tomoz App Launched" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/tomoz-app-launched</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/tomoz-app-launched"><![CDATA[<p>I made an app that, allows picking of whatever calendars you want, and shows only what is happening tomorrow in a simple agenda view.</p>

<p>Also supports export to markdown and other formats.</p>

<p>Over 200 downloads in fhe first two days.</p>

<p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/tomoz/id6748755747">Get on the app store</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I made an app that, allows picking of whatever calendars you want, and shows only what is happening tomorrow in a simple agenda view.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Andy aiming to run Piccalilli full time</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/we-re-aiming-to-run-piccalilli-full-time" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Andy aiming to run Piccalilli full time" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/we%E2%80%99re-aiming-to-run-piccalilli-full-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/we-re-aiming-to-run-piccalilli-full-time"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>I think courses are going to be the main driver of keeping the lights on <em>and</em> pushing us towards full time work on Piccalilli. Now that we have a nice system for publishing courses, the velocity will of course increase.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think courses are going to be the main driver of keeping the lights on and pushing us towards full time work on Piccalilli. Now that we have a nice system for publishing courses, the velocity will of course increase.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accessibility Development Digest</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/accessibility-development-digest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accessibility Development Digest" /><published>2025-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/accessibility-development-digest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/accessibility-development-digest"><![CDATA[<p>The is a selection of favourited articles in my RSS reader app around web design and accessibility</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://adrianroselli.com/2025/07/arty-could-get-you-sued.html">#ARTY Could Get You Sued</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://adrianroselli.com/2025/07/check-uncheck-all-in-a-table.html">Check / Uncheck all in a Table</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://adrianroselli.com/2025/04/automated-wcag-testing-is-grrreat.html">Automated WCAG Testing Is Grrreat!</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/07/design-patterns-ai-interfaces/">Design Patterns For AI Interfaces</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/06/can-good-ux-protect-older-users-digital-scams/">Can Good UX Protect Older Users From Digital Scams?</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/05/design-system-in-90-days/">Design System In 90 Days</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/04/what-mean-site-be-keyboard-navigable/">What Does It Really Mean For A Site To Be Keyboard Navigable</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/04/fostering-accessibility-culture/">Fostering An Accessibility Culture</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.tempertemper.net/blog/wcag-aaa-in-language-i-can-understand">WCAG AAA in language I can understand</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.tempertemper.net/blog/wcag-2-2-in-language-i-can-understand">WCAG 2.2 in language I can understand</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.tempertemper.net/blog/making-sense-of-accessibility-and-the-law">Accessibility and the Law</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The is a selection of favourited articles in my RSS reader app around web design and accessibility]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rebranding and design costs</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rebranding and design costs" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/the-not-quite-new-gov-uk-brand-blog-beeps"><![CDATA[<p>Making intuitive interfaces and design systems that work for everyone is hard and takes time, but often the expectation is to deliver quickly.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Oh, and about the cost
A bit of hubbub has been made about the cost of the brand refresh, lamenting that a chunk of change (about half a million) was given to an agency to ‘only’ change a colour and move Dot.</p>

  <p>This perspective only focuses on the logo, and completely ignores the other additions to the brand that are being introduced over time. It ignores that everything was tested, prototyped, refined, and tested again dozens of times with members of the public. It might not be obvious from a single side-by-side graphic, but a lot of time went into interrogating what we had and experimenting with what could be added.</p>

  <p>It was the full-time salaried efforts of dozens of design, development, and delivery specialists for more than a year. By that metric, it’s actually quite cheap.</p>

  <p>The place we landed was well-considered and intentional. Just because the destination of that journey was a logo that intentionally looks quite similar to the existing one doesn’t mean that the money was wasted, or that creating something radically different would have been better value for money.</p>

  <p>A holiday isn’t a waste of money just because you return home at the end of it.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><category term="brand" /><category term="GDS" /><category term="government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making intuitive interfaces and design systems that work for everyone is hard and takes time, but often the expectation is to deliver quickly.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Context engineering</title><link href="https://thechels.uk/context-engineering" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Context engineering" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thechels.uk/context-engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thechels.uk/context-engineering"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The term <strong>context engineering</strong> has recently started to gain traction as a better alternative to prompt engineering. I like it. I think this one may have sticking power.</p>

  <p>Here’s an example tweet <a href="https://twitter.com/tobi/status/1935533422589399127">from Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke</a>:</p>

  <p>I really like the term “context engineering” over prompt engineering.</p>

  <p>It describes the core skill better: the art of providing all the context for the task to be plausibly solvable by the LLM.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Mat</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The term context engineering has recently started to gain traction as a better alternative to prompt engineering. I like it. I think this one may have sticking power. Here’s an example tweet from Shopify CEO Tobi Lutke: I really like the term “context engineering” over prompt engineering. It describes the core skill better: the art of providing all the context for the task to be plausibly solvable by the LLM.]]></summary></entry></feed>